Okay, so in this video we're
going to cover an important
quality management tool
called the Pareto Chart.
Now the Pareto chart is a type of
histogram.
It is a specialised type
of histogram that shows
critical issues in descending
order of frequency.
Or it could be showing the causes of an
issue in descending order of frequency.
And it's a histogram.
It is a histogram and a histogram is
basically a bar chart, but it's a special
So if you look at an example of the Pareto
chart here, we'll see that this Pareto
chart has a bar chart here, and then there
is also a line graph across the top.
And you'll notice there
are two y-axis, one on
the left-and-side, one
on the right-in-side.
The left-hand y-axis refers
to the bar chart, and the
right-hand refers to the red
frequency line across the top.
Now, as I said, Proto chart
is showing critical issues or
the causes of an issue in a
descending order of frequency.
So in this example here, then, we are
looking at the number of customer complaints.
So regardless of, you
know, what the situation
is, we're getting some
customer complaints.
So what are the biggest causes of customer
complaints?
And that is then shown on this graphic.
So the causes of complaints then,
A, B, C, Claims?
C, D, all the way to G, you know, whatever
A, B, C, D are, you know, it's irrelevant.
But these are the causes of complaints.
And then on the left-hand y-axis,
we show the number of complaints.
And the right-hand of Y-axis is showing
you a percentage, right, the cumulative
percentage, which refers to this red line
across the top.
So A, whatever A is,
that accounts for the most
number of complaints
that we are receiving.
B, whatever B is, accounts
for the next most number
of complaints, and so
on and so forth, right?
So it's showing critical issues in
descending order of frequency.
Now, what the line graph across the top is
showing, right, is a
cumulative percentage.
So A then accounts for
maybe, you know, around
35% of all of the
issues that we're gained.
A and B together accounts for maybe about
70% of all of the customer complaints.
So A accounts for around 35% of all of the
customer complaints.
A and B together accounts for around 70%
of all customer complaints.
A, B and C together
accounts for approximately
around about 80% of
all customer complaints.
And so on and so forth until we get to
100%.
Now the whole principle behind the Pareto
chart rests with what is known as the
80-20 rule, also known as Pareto's Law,
also known as Pareto's Law.
And it's worth just
giving you a little bit of
background about where
this 80-20 rule came from.
This is not something necessarily that
will be asked on the exam, but just to
understand this graph
here, just to understand
exactly what the Pareto chart is showing.
right it's good just to mention it at
least now this guy Pareto Wilfredo Pareto
that was his name he was an economist he
had nothing to do with project management
he was actually an Italian economist and
this was back around the late 1800 early
1900s type of time frame so we're going
back quite a while and when he was
analyzing the economies of Italy and
Europe and other countries he saw one
basic theme over and over
again now obviously I I'm
summarizing and generalizing
here, but we're just talking
about this at a very,
very, very high level.
But essentially what he was saying is 80%
of a nation's wealth, right, or land in
those days, 80% of nation's land is
generally owned by 20% of the population.
And so we see this 80-20 rule over and
over again.
So for a typical business,
for example, 80% of
your revenues comes
from 20% of your customers.
And so when it comes to
defect management, 80% of
your defects are as a
result of 20% of the causes.
So if you can identify those
20% of the causes and fix
those 20%, you've basically
fixed 80% of all of your issues.
So if you look at this graph, and if I
didn't tell you anything about this graph,
and I just told you, or
rather I just asked you,
which issues do we
need to focus on the most?
Immediately you look at
this graph and say, well,
A and B, that's what we
want to focus on the most.
And that is the whole principle behind
proto-chart.
This is what we want to look at.
We want to fix A and B.
If we fix A and B, then A and B account
for 70% of all.
issues.
So we fix A and B, we have fixed 70% of
all of our issues.
And so you can use Pareto chart for
continuous improvement.
We want to make small continuous
improvement steps.
So what should we be focusing on?
We should be focusing on, in this case,
on A and B.
Once we have fixed, if we
can fix A and B, we have
fixed in this case, we fixed
70% of all of our issues.
And that really is about as much as what
you need.
for the PNP exam regarding Pareto charts.
So again, Pareto chart is just a
histogram.
It's a specialised type of histogram and
it's showing critical issues in descending
order of frequency or the causes of an
issue in descending order of frequency.